你们感觉到鼓舞了吗?
Do you feel the spirit?
在犹大王亚撒登基的第39年,他的脚得了病
And in the 39th year of his reign,asa was diseased in his feet,
直到病入膏肓
until the disease was exceedingly great.
他没有乞求神的帮助, 而是去看医生
Yet he didn't seek help from the lord,but from the physicians.
今天, 去看医生不再有什么错
Now,there is nothing wrong with seeing a doctor.
但是医生能用耶稣给他信徒的神力,去治病救人吗?
But can a doctor heal through the power that jesus gave his disciples?
相信科学的人们被蒙着眼睛走完一生
Men of science can walk through life with blindfolds
从不知道如果没有上帝的搀扶
never knowing that you or i could not take a single step
你我连一步也走不了
if we were not uplifted by god.
Agnes, 谢谢你让我用上帝的爱来引导你
Agnes,thank you for letting me be an instrument of god's love for you.
信上帝...一切皆有可能
In faith...all things are possible.
我的朋友们, 让Agnes在今天,在这个教堂, 感受到信仰的力量吧
My friends,I want you to let agnes feel the wave of faith in this church here today
让上帝牵引她
lifting her into god's hands.
你能做到的! 加油, 我的姐妹
You can do it!Come on,sister.
赞美耶稣! 感谢上帝!
Praise jesus!Thank you,god!
感谢神!
Thank you,lord!
不!
no!
孩子!
Son!
爸爸, 我想我要看医生
Dad,I think i need a doctor.
你还记得我的DVD播放机吗?
Did you remember my dvd player?
唔, 如果你想要的话,就不应该走的时候丢下它
Well,if you wanted it,you shouldn't have left it behind when you moved out.
现在我明白了,在录像机上看A片太麻烦了
Now I get it.It's a drag watching porn on vhs.
我看好了就给你打电话
I'll call you as soon as I'm done with it.
如果你赶紧装个电话的话
That's if you ever get a phone installed.
噢得了吧, 我自己过去拿
Oh,forget it.I'll come by and get it myself.
下班后好吗? 礼拜三怎么样?
After work?Thursday?
我礼拜三不在家
Won't be home thursday.
没关系, 我有你家钥匙,我可以自由进出
No problem,I still have a key.I can let myself in and out.
我想也许我明天就可以带给你
I guess maybe I could bring it in tomorrow.
对了, 你要按多少次暂停?
After all,how many times can you hit pause
就是lindsay lohan赢得拼字比赛的镜头?,(电影:贱女孩)
at the part where lindsay lohan wins the spelling bee?
你对会拼字的女孩这么有瘾?
What is it about girls who can spell?
是数学竞赛
It's math contest.
你对会算术的女孩这么有瘾?
What is it about girls who can count?
那晚要打扑克是不是?
It's poker night,isn't it?
几个星期前你就说带我一起玩,别再找借口了
You said weeks ago that I could play.Stop making excuses.
我得走了, 这里到处都是病人
Gotta go.Building full of sick people.
如果我抓紧点, 就能躲开他们
If I hurry,maybe I can avoid them.
腹部系列检查显示无梗阻
the abdominal series showed no evidence of obstruction.
吃了什么东西?
What'd you have to eat?
鸡肉三明治, 我们云游四处,经常吃快餐
Chicken sandwich.We travel.Lots of fast food.
谢谢你, 几乎感觉不到疼
Thank you.I barely felt it.
不用谢
You're welcome.
上帝告诉我你人很好
God told me you were kind.
你对上帝说话?
You talk to god?
上帝经常降临到他身上来指引他人
God's presence often descends on boyd to help him guide others.
已经很久了?
This been going on long?
从他十岁那年开始
Since he was ten.
上帝说我将遇见一位女医生...
God told me I would meet a woman healer...
她对她的一个男同事怀恨在心
who was harboring vengeful thoughts about a man she works with.
那就是上帝的工作
That's god's job.
我会记住的
I'll keep that in mind.
他的尿液很稀
His urine is dilute.
那是什么意思?
What does that mean?
那意味着可能由于某些原因,他的肾不再以应有的方式工作
It could mean that for some reason hikidneys aren't purifying the way they should,
导致他体内的毒素不断累积
which would let toxins accumulate in his body.
我们打算验血, 看能发现什么
We'll run the blood work and see what it tells us.
谢谢你, 我很感激
Thank you,I appreciate it.
上帝和他对话?
God talks to him?
那不是什么精神病,只是一种宗教信仰而已
it's not psychosis,he's just religious.
验血结果唯一有医学意义的是低钠
The only medical issue that showed up on the blood work is low sodium.
不尽然, 对上帝讲话, 那是宗教信仰,听到上帝对你讲话, 那是精神病
No,you talk to god,you're religious.God talks to you,you're psychotic.
很多人把他们的宗教体验当作一种,实实在在的东西而不是象征
A lot of people experience their religion as something more than symbolic.
你在神学院的时候上帝对你讲过话吗?
God ever talk to you when you where in the seminary?
没有
No.
上帝损失了, 我们得到你
God's loss,our gain.
他不是个精神病就是个装神弄鬼的
He's either psychotic or a scam artist.
他真的令人印象深刻
He was actually really impressive.
是啊...燃烧的灌丛...估计挺精彩的
Well,yeah...with the burning bush and all,it's quite the show.
他很聪明, 有礼貌, 而且有气质,不像只有15岁
He was intelligent,polite,dignified.He's not a typical 15-year-old.
他还告诉Cameron上帝叫她别再,为论文的事恨我了
And he told cameron god wants her to stop being pissed at me over the article.
上帝知道你剽窃了Cameron的论文?
God knows you stole cameron's article?
他知道她"怀恨在心"
He knows she's "harboring vengeful thoughts."
我已经不介意
I'm over it.
得了, 我从你们的肢体语言,就能看出一堵柏林墙
Yeah,I can tell that from the berlin wall of body language between you.
他要看不出来我才吃惊呢,低钠
I'm shocked that he picked up on it.Low sodium.
查过阿狄森氏病吗?,(一种肾上腺疾病)
Check for addison's?
无色素沉着, 而且钾的水平也正常
No pigmentation and potassium levels were normal.
肝硬化呢?
Cirrhosis?
肝脏很好. 转氨酶水平未见异常
Liver feels fine.Transaminases are normal.
监控他的盐摄入量以纠正低钠
We should monitor his saline intake to correct the low sodium.
每小时每升不超过一毫当量
No more than one meq per liter per hour.
再去查查病人的既往史
And let's push the patient history.
看看病人有没有服用过毒品或幻药,我再去看看
See if there's any evidence of drugs or other delusions.I'll take care of it.
你打算去和病人谈谈?
You're gonna talk to a patient?
上帝才和他谈
God talks to him.
认为我比上帝还能干也太狂了
It'd be arrogant of me to assume that I'm better than god.
那么, 你是个"靠信仰治病的人"
So,you're a "faith healer."
我这么说没有轻蔑你吧?
Or is that a pejorative?
是不是叫"神圣健康计划"好听些?
Do you prefer something like "divine health management"?
我以为上帝已经和你打过招呼我要来了
I though god might have mentioned that I was coming.
我喜欢那个称呼, House医生
I'm okay with "faith healer",dr. House.
有两下子, 你还不如直接说...
That's a nice one.You didn't even go with...
"我看到了白大褂上有个H"
"I see an h and a medical coat."
护士们经常谈论你
The nurses talk about you a lot.
别信她们, 我随身带着一只袜子的
Ah,don't believe them.I keep a sock in my pants.
信仰, 无知的另一种说法, 是不是?
Faith,that's anoth word for ignorance,isn't it?
我无法理解人们怎么可以如此相信,没有根据的事情
I never understood how people could be so proud
而且还为此感到骄傲,就好像那是伟大的成就
of believing in something with no proof at all.Like that's an achievement.
上帝要我们信任他,你不信任一个人就无法去爱他
God's asking for our trust.You can't love somebody and not trust them.
信任是需要争取的
Trust has to be earned.
你不能相信一个躲在神龛里的人
You can't trust someone hiding in a closet.
你不相信任何人
You don't trust anyone.
你看起来很清醒
You seem lucid.
思维不混乱, 精神也还好,你在吃什么药?
There's no confusion,no lethargy.What drugs have you been taking?
没什么药, 就一些阿司匹林
Nothing.Some aspirin.
我精力放在别的事上, 忘记吃饭了--,你知道接下来会怎样
I get focused on something,I forget to eat--next thing you know,
我饿得头晕
I've got a hunger headache.
可以吃阿司匹林和上医院
So aspirin and hospitals are okay.
这还真有意思了
That's an interesting attitude for someone
你不是劝说别人别找医生吗?
who's kept any number of people from getting medical help.
我相信上帝并不意味着,不相信细菌和毒物
Just because i believe in prayer doesn't mean I don't believe in germs and toxins.
那瓶子以前开过的
That bottle's been opened before.
你在饮水机那里灌的
You refilled it at the water cooler.
是的
Yes.
多久灌一次?
How often do you do that?
一小时灌几次, 他喜欢喝水
A few times an hour.He likes to stay hydrated.
你认为可能有细菌跑进去了?
You think germs might have gotten in?
我认为可能有水跑进去了
I think water might have gotten in.
我们可以对你的疼痛调整疗法
We can adjust your pain meds.
又调整?
Again?
假如我们增加给你的氧可酮
Suppose we incase your oxycodone.
你我都知道之所以我现在还能,清醒地和你说话
We both know the only reason i'm talking lucidly now
是因为今早我没把药全吃下去
is because I did not take my full dose this morning.
你已经尽力了
You've done your best.
而我也曾是个好士兵
And I have been a good soldier.
该是一切结束的时候了
It's time we accept it's over.
你计划中的那个旅行怎么办?
What about the trip you were talking about taking?
十几岁的时候你就想去看看佛罗伦萨了
You've wanted to see florence since you were a teenager,right?
去不了了, 难道还整"药"待发么?
Yeah,go now.All drugged up.
我梦想的旅行可不是这样的
It's not exactly the trip i've been dreaming of.
好的, 你很坚强
Okay,you're strong.
你正面对它
You're dealing with this.
止疼药组合正确的话一定可以,我们能找到那个组合
And there is the right combination of pain meds out there.And we'll find it.
不要对我们绝望
Don't give up on us.
还有, 别被那声音吓到
And don't be startled by the sound you're about to hear.
请原谅
Excuse me.
我这个朋友...有点边界纠纷
I have a friend with boundary issues.
你就不能再等5分钟吗?
Can this wait five minutes?
她要死了吗?
Is she dying?
是的
Yeah.
在我们结束这次谈话以前?
Before the end of this consult?
他们会为你的自以为是立碑的
They could build monuments to your self-centeredness.
一个15岁病人, 靠信仰治病,自称是上帝的热线电话
Patient.15-year-old.Faith healer.Hotline to god.
什么症状?
What are his symptoms?
他不是什么圣人
He is not a saint.
他通过观察, 倾听, 推理来发现,别人的生活中发生了什么事
He figures out what's going on in people's lives by watching,listening,deducing.
担心他侵犯你的专利?
And you're worried about trademark infringement?
然后他假传上帝的建议,看他们欢欣鼓舞, 玩弄大众
Then he passes on advice from god so he can watch them jump.It's a power trip.
这一点你俩有所不同,他因什么入院?
Ah,and there the similarities end.Why is he here?
我为人类感到可怕
I fear for the human race.
一个少年自称替上帝传声
A teenager claims to be the voice of god
拥有高等学历的人还听他的
and people with advanced degrees are listening.
大多数美国人都有自己的神
The majority of americans believe in a personal god.
他是什么症状?
What are his symptoms?
大范围腹痛, 低钠
Massive cramps,low sodium.
原来是因为不停喝水,上帝告诉他要净化身体
Turns out he's been drinking water non-stop.God told him to purify his body.
大量摄入水会引起低钠
Huge water intake would cause low sodium.
还会引起腹痛, 我知道了
Which would cause the cramping.Yeah,I got it.
就这样了? 你解决了
What,that's it?You solved it.
你把我叫出来就是因为他的信仰使你很烦?
You just brought me out here to rant because faith annoys you?
嗯, 他好多了
Mm-hmm.He's all better.
我能够理解,人要给自己定位在一个坑里
You know,I'd get it if people were just looking for a way to fill the holes.
但他们要占有这个坑, 一世生活在坑里
But they want the holes.They wanna live in the holes.
别人朝他的坑里填土, 就惹恼他了
And they go nuts when someone else pours dirt in their holes.
从坑里出来, 你们这些人!
Climb out of your holes,people!
在山顶大声宣告,让声音传遍山峦和每寸土地
Go tell it on the mountain over the hills and everywhere
在山顶大声宣告,救世主耶稣已经诞生
go tell it on the mountain  that jesus christ is born
在山顶大声宣告,让声音传遍山峦和每寸土地
go tell it on the mountain over the hills and everywhere
在山顶大声宣告,救世主耶稣已经诞生
go tell it on the mountain that jesus christ is born
boyd, 你没事吧?
boyd,are you all right?
在山顶大声宣告,让声音传遍山峦和...
Go tell it on the mountain boyd.Over the hills and...
我们走, 能告诉我你的名字吗?
come on,let's go.Can you tell me your name?
你知道这是哪里吗?
Do you know where you are?
Boyd?
上帝要你别感到害怕
God doesn't want you to be afraid.
他派我来治好你
He sent me here to heal you.
你以为他无法听到祷告, 他全能听到,甚至你未说出口的
You think he hasn't heard you prayers,but he heard them all.Even the ones you didn't say.
对不起Boyd, 我带你回病房
Sorry.Boyd,come on.Let's get you back to your room.
有信仰, 一切皆有可能
In faith,all things are possible.
我们走
Let's go.
主...我请求你解除你的儿女的痛苦
Lord...I call on you to relieve the suffering of your daughter.
- Grace?,- 让她恢复吧
- Grace?,- And make her whole again.
嘿, 你在干什么? 怎么了?
hey,hey!What are you doing?What is this?
他刚刚复杂局灶性癫痫发作,失去了判断力
he's just had a complex partial seizure.His disoriented.
他不知道他正在干什么
He doesn't know what he's doing.
那现在就把他带回他的病房
Well get him back to his room--now.
你没事吧?
You okay?
我们能确定他得的是癫痫吗?
are we certain he even had a seizure?
就因为唱着赞歌去治疗别人?,他一直这么干, 不是吗?
Hymn singing and healing.He does it all the time,doesn't he?
这可真够有意思的
Isn't it interesting
宗教行为和疯狂行动太像了,简直分不出来
that religious behavior is so close to being crazy,we can't tell 'em apart.
行为重复, 缺乏感觉和意识,那就是癫痫
The repetition,the lack of affect and awareness.It was a seizure.
感染?
Infection?
没有发烧
No fever.
可能是威尔逊病. 或者是糖原贮积病
Could be wilson'S.Or maybe it's a glycogen storage disease.
或者脑瘤
Or a brain tumor.
还有结节性硬化症
Or tuberous sclerosis.
唔, 怎么解决呢?
How to settle this?
应该让我们的病人去问问上帝,或者给他的大脑来次核磁共振
We could ask our patient to ask god.Or we could mri his brain.
你们认为如何?,因为我现在什么都可以接受
Which way do you wanna go?'Cause I'm open to all possibilities.
House! 你怎么能让一个,病情不稳定的病人在走廊里游荡?
House!Why the hell do you let an unstable patient wander the hallways?
她挣脱了皮带
His leash broke.
临终病人最不愿听到的,是有人拿康复来开她的玩笑
The last thing a terminal patient needs is to hear somebody taunt them with a cure.
她感到很荒诞, 很生气
She was freaked,she was angry.
可她不感到荒诞和生气了,现在是你
And now she's not freaked and angry.And you are.
她说她"感觉好多了"
She says she's "feeling better".
也许没有载歌载舞
Maybe not singing and dancing,
但她感觉是这几个月来最开心的一次
but she's feeling just a little bit happy for the first time in months.
突然的止痛会带来欣快的感觉
Sudden drop in pain can create euphoria.
为什么不让她去度假呢?
Why don't you let her have her vacation?
这下好了, 当她结束度假
Oh,that's great.And when the vacation's over,
然后再度坠入残酷的现实?,她在和疾病抗争!
when she crash lands from all this denial?She was dealing with her illness.
你提高了她的期望
Now her expectations are rising.
你又不用陪着她-
And you're not the one who has to be there
面对她心中升起的虚假希望
when all that false hope gets yanked out from under her.
你们是不是无事可做?
Don't you guys have anything to do?
你这样医治别人有多久了?
How long have you been healing people?
你相信我能治病?
You believe that's what I'm doing?
我希望能
I'd like to.
但你不信
But you don'T.
为什么要做你不想做的?
Why do you always do things you don't wanna do?
不要紧, 不必回答我
It's okay,I don't expect a real answer.
上帝可能希望你忘记那些不快
You know,god would probably want you to take that stick out of your butt and get over this.
如果宇宙中真有超人一等的神
If there is some higher order running the universe,
他很可能是超出人类理解力的
it's probably so different from anything our species can conceive,
揣测他的想法没有意义
there's no point in even thinking about it.
不过我还是怀疑,他是否会照顾到我的心情
But I doubt it gives a damn about my butt.
所以你相信上帝也许真的存在,但你就是不去想他?
So you believe god might exist,but you don't think about it?
这个问题非常重要--
It's the most important issue--
我认为企鹅还研究核物理学呢
I think penguins might as well speculate about nuclear physics.
我们为什么谈这个?
Why are we having this conversation?
什么? 我只是好奇
What?I'm curious.
不能先告诉别人-,"你只是同事而不是朋友"
You cannot tell someone they are your colleague and not a friend
然后又随意地和她探讨死后的事
and then casually chat about the afterlife.
你真的在记分?
you actually keep score?
你的MRI检查结果还没出来
Your mri results aren't done yet.
回你自己病房去, 不许唱歌
Go back to your room.No singing.
唔, 查出来为什么低钠你得了一分
Well,you would get a point for figuring why the low sodium.
我的分怎么来的?
What are my guy's points for?
你关于Cameron和Foreman之间口角,的把戏确实玩的不错
Your trick about the spat between dr. Cameron and dr. Foreman apparently impressed someone.
第二分呢?
And the second point?
是不是因为我治好了Grace?
Do you think it could be because I healed grace?
她回来看过我, 我喜欢她
She's been back to see me.I like her.
你喜欢的是捣乱
You like messing with people.
所以你跑这儿来了
That's why you're here now.
也许你认为你的电池动力来自上帝,也许你不
Maybe you think that your batteries are powered by god,maybe you don'T.
不管怎样, 你喜欢你现在干的
Either way,you enjoy what you do.
是的, 我喜欢帮助人们
Yes.I like helping people.
当看到他们的负担全都飞走的,面部表情时, 我能感到心潮澎湃
I get a rush when I see the look on their faces when they realize their burdens are gone.
不过你很快就跑到另一个州了
Mm,but you make sure you're in the next state by the time
那时病人的脑内啡耗尽,关节炎又回来了
the endorphins wear off and the arthritis comes back.
那不可能发生
That doesn't happen.
噢, 你做过长期跟踪研究?
Oh,you do extensive follow-up studies?
上帝告诉我的
God told me.
你看看, 那就不公平了,我们正玩得好好的
See,that's not fair.We were having fun.
当你扔了那么大一个炸弹后想让,被开玩笑的人再保持理性是很难的
It's hard to keep sniping rationally when you throw a bomb like that in there.
他也提到你了
He spoke with me about you too.
原谅我的敌人?
Forgive my enemies?
当水星逆行的时候,永远不要和金牛座约会?
Never date a taurus when mercury's in retrograde?
这些我自己也能学会--通过惨痛教训
Yeah,I learned that one myself--the hard way.
上帝说你找借口单独待着
God says you look for excuses to be alone.
瞧瞧, 那正是一种听起来非常玄妙
See,that is exactly the kind of brilliance that sounds deep,
其实可以用来形容任何一个
but you could say it about any person
不渴望和他见到的每个人都有深交的人
who doesn't pine for the social approval of everyone he meets.
你那么做可以聪明地推断我是什么人,而且使自己看起来还不像弱智
Which you were cleverly able to deduce about me but not being a moron.
告诉上帝下次具体点
Next time tell god to be more specific.
上帝希望你邀请Wilson医生参加牌局
God wants you to invite dr. Wilson to your poker game.
不要和我的病人交谈
Don't talk to my patient.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
我的病人在走廊里无意中碰到你的病人,于是你火了
You get all huffy when my patient stumbles into yours in the hallway.
但是你不能和我的病人什么都谈
But you got no qualms about chatting my guy up.
有意思, 就像猜密码一样
This is fun,it's like password.
继续, 当我发现你他妈的在说什么的,时候我就会加入的
Keep talking,I'll jump in when I get a clue what the hell you're talking about.
上帝知道牌局的事
God knows about my poker game.
你认为是我告诉了他?
You think I told him?
如果不是那样,我可要开始每周上教堂了
Either that or I start going to church every sunday.
会和保龄球时间冲突的
That would mess with my bowling league.
House, 除了朝他吼让他滚回自己的病房
House,aside from yelling at him to get back to his room,
我从没有和你的病人讲过话
I've never spoken to your patient.
核磁共振显示有一个区域不正常
mri shows an abnormal area.
结节性脑硬化
Tuberous sclerosis.
它邻近的部分是引起一切症状的根源
It's the right neighborhood.Accounts for all the symptoms.
所有的症状
All of them.
首先确认是脑皮质结节
Leading cortical tuber's identifiable.
我们可以手术去除
We can do this surgically.
去祝贺我们的病人吧
Tell our patient congratulations.
那些和上帝的对话很快就要成为历史了
Soon these chats with god will be a thing of the past.
天平向凡人这边倾斜
Tie goes to the mortal.
你知道在Lourdes的天主教堂里,一直都有一名医生的吗?
Did you know the catholic church keeps a doctor at lourdes?
他每天听到的都是一样的
He hears the same thing every day.
可是在数以千计的声称好转的案例中
But out of the thousands of cases of people who have claimed to feel better,
只有很少一部分被教堂确认是奇迹
the catholic church has only recognized a handful as miracles.
可他们确实认识到了这很小一部分
But they do recognize a handful.
唔, 他们只是一个教堂
Well,they're a church.
他们就是干这个的
It's what they do.
在过去的几年里, 我的世界越来越小
Look,for the past couple of years,the world's been getting smaller.
8个月, 6个月
Eight months,six months.
我看到一部电影的宣传片
I watch a trailer for a movie...
就会想, 正式片上映的时候我还在吗?
and I think,am I gonna be here when that comes out?
也许那里还有一道地平线
But maybe there is still a horizon out there.
你知道, 也许...也许我能做个,一年的计划, 甚至两年
You know,maybe...maybe I can make plans for a year from now.Two years.
我喜欢这个前景
I like the view.
那是个谎言,如果你相信, 你会被害惨的...
The view is a lie.And if you believe it,you're going to crash so hard...
我再给你的肝拍几张片子吧
let me take new images of your liver.
你不能接受那可能是事实
You can't accept that it could be true.
唔, 如果是事实,你不应该害怕去证明它
Well,if it is true,you shouldn't be afraid of proving it.
结节性脑硬化是遗传性疾病
tuberous sclerosis is a genetic disorder.
它导致体内各部分出现良性小肿瘤,在这个病例中, 是大脑
It causes small,benign tumors to grow in various parts of the body.In this case,the brain.
你说是良性的
You said benign.
仅仅是可能. 可不管是不是良性,长的可真不是地方
They probably are.But benign or not,they're not in a good location.
必须切除掉
We need to remove them.
你们说的是脑外科手术?
You're talking brain surgery?
他的症状越来越严重了,这说明肿瘤正在生长
His symptoms are getting worse which means the tumors are growing.
手术将解决一切问题,包括电解质失衡, 癫痫, 幻听
Surgery will correct it all.The chemical imbalance,the seizures,the auditory hallucinations.
幻觉?
Hallucinations?
不手术, 情况会越来越糟,甚至危及生命
Without the surgery,it's just gonna get worse.It might even be fatal.
做了手术, 你的儿子会变成一个,15岁普通男孩
With the surgery,your son should be a perfectly normal 15-year-old boy.
我不普通
I'm not normal.
我需要你跟我的病人谈谈
I need you to talk to my patient.
这个我来
I'll get this one.
我怎么觉得你要密谋称霸世界呢?
Why do I have the feeling you're plotting world domination?
摩西拒绝手术
Moses is refusing surgery.
你有这个本事
You have a gift.
人们感激你,因为你告诉他们要死
People thank you for telling them they're gonna die.
如果我能说服他手术
If I can get him to agree to surgery,
我要参加扑克
I want in on the poker game.
你为了参加一个愚蠢的游戏,宁愿让一个孩子去死?
You would let this kid die,,just to get into a stupid game?
你宁可让他死也不让我参加?
You'd let him die just to keep me out?
嗨
Hi.
我是Wilson医生
I'm dr. Wilson.
我知道会换人来说
I knew they'd send somebody else.
这上帝还真多嘴
That god has a big mouth.
House.
House
我想知道...
Can I ask...
为什么你不想切掉肿瘤?
why you don't want the tumors removed?
上帝给我肿瘤, 自有他的理由
God put them there for a reason.
你认为上帝把肿瘤当做电话和你交流吗?
you think god needs a telephone in your head to talk to you?
上帝不是无处不在的吗?
Isn't he everywhere?
难道还要靠长途电话?
It's not a long distance call,is it?
这是上帝行事的方法
This is the way god does things.
利用自然的法则
Through natural law.
如果上帝整天到处显示他的神力
If he went around doing big, flashy miracles all the time,
人们就不需要信仰了
nobody would need faith.
为什么其他人需要通过信仰
How come everyone else needs faith,
而你却能直接在耳边听到上帝的声音
but you just get the guy screaming his existence in your ear?
换你说
Your turn.
你认为上帝想要你死吗?
Do you think god wants you to die?
上帝经常这样对待他选中的人
this is the way that the lord often is with his chosen ones.
最喜欢的人受到最多的考验
He gives the most trials to those that he loves the most.
说得真好听
How sweet.
你不用履行你的职责
You abdicate your authority.
减少了许多做父母的烦恼
Avoid those tricky parental issues
如果不能决定要不要让孩子16岁开车
like wther to let him drive at 16.
就让他15岁就死掉
Just let him die at 15.
那么说你觉得你儿子是
So you believe your son is...
恩,一个圣徒
um,a saint.
我是这么理解的
The way i understand it,
圣徒的一个特质是谦逊
one of the hallmarks of a saint is humility.
一个谦逊的人
Someone with true humility
应该会想到这种可能性
would consider the possibility that...
那就是神根本没有选中他
god hadn't chosen him for that kind of honor.
他会想到有可能...
He'd consider the possibility that...
他只是病了
he just had an illness.
你有控制别人思想的天分
You have a gift for manipulation.
我会注意聆听
I listen.
我会和他们交谈
I have an actual conversation with people.
这样居然可以奇迹般地让他们合作
Which,shockingly, does raise the odds they'll be cooperative.
这是我的台词
That's what I'm saying.
你看透了那个孩子, 你就可以控制他了
You read that kid, and you manipulated the hell out of him.
记得带椒盐卷饼
Bring pretzels.
一听声音就知道是你
I know that knock!
你有钥匙, 我不会给你开的
Use your key, I'm not getting up.
牌局要到明天晚上
Game's not till tomorrow night.
你手里拿的也不是椒盐卷饼
And those aren't pretzels.
这是几张Grace Palmieri的癌症CT片
I took some images of grace palmieri's cancer.
怎么了?
Yeah?
她的肿瘤变小了
Her tumor has shrunk.
别告诉我的那个病人
Don't tell my patient.
我要这个奇迹女病人的所有资料
I want all the records on miracle woman
所有的检查报告和治疗方法
Every test,every treatment she's ever had.
她们在医院里回答过的所有问题
Every question she's ever answered in this hospital.
还有前任医师发过来的资料
And anything sent from previous doctors.
可能的话查下出生时的情况
Go back to neonatal if you have...
"不要让他们见面"那个字你听不懂?
which part of "keep them away from each other" confused you?
他们是朋友
They're friends.
她认为他救了她的命
She thinks he saved her life.
于是我们很乐意提供医学证明
And we've obligingly offered medical proof
证明他的错觉是有科学根据的
that his delusions are true.
他们不同意进行手术
They've withdrawn permission for the surgery.
我已经让律师去处理了
I've put the lawyers on it.
她的肿瘤变小了?
Her tumor shrank?
我会处理的
I'm on it.
告诉那个小耶稣,我们需要额外的24小时
Tell jesus that we need another 24 hours
来纠正他的钠离子水平
to normalize his sodium level.
早就纠正了
He's already normalized.
实际是告诉圣约瑟,(耶稣肉身的父亲)
Actually,tell joseph.
耶稣能看穿你撒谎
Jesus'll know you're lying.
我要你, Foreman还有Cameron
And I want you and foreman and cameron
逐行逐字研究那个女病人的资料
to go over every line of every file on that woman.
我们不是要救那个男孩吗?
Isn't he the one we're supposed to save?
救他的唯一办法
The only way to save him
就是证明她没有康复
is to prove that she is still dying.
磁核共振仪没问题
Mri machine checks out.
也可能是放射科医生误操作了
Maybe the radiologist mischarted which machine they used.
两个我都检查过了
I checked both.
这太变态了
This is insane.
我们居然对康复进行诊断
We're diagnosing a recovery.
会不会是六个月以前?
What about six months ago?
在那时操作有误
Maybe there was a malfunction on her before pictures.
某些阴影会使肿瘤看起来--
Some shadow that made the tumor
比实际的大
look bigger than it really was.
我去查查看
I'll go see what I can find out.
可能是放射治疗的延迟效应
Maybe it's a delayed effect from radiation.
有时候需要一段时间
Sometimes it can take a while.
她已经六个月没放疗了
She hasn't had radiation for six months.
这有可能
Here.
不可能, 记录上...
Nowhere. Her records...
每个家庭都有一堆电器会释放辐射
there's about a dozen appliances in every home that give off radiation.
那点辐射量对老鼠都没有影响
Dosages that wouldn't hurt a hamster
甚至整年把它绑在电器上也不会
if it was tied to the machine for a year.
只有当电器运转正常时
If the machine's operating properly.
有时候肿瘤自己就变小了
Sometimes remissions just happen.
如果我们没有去她家看看,你以为House会欣然接受这种解释吗?
You think house will just shrug and say that if one of us doesn't check the home?
K对9对
Kings on 9s.
我赢了
**Thank you.
Wilson, 这位是...
Wilson,this is...
洗衣店的
uh,dry cleaner,
税务员
tax accountant,
巴士站工作人员
guy from the bus stop.
这是Wilson
This is wilson.
他怎么有名字?
How come he gets a name?
资格比较老
Seniority.
大家好
Hello.
发现什么没?
Find anything?
你知道有多少电器有辐射么?
You have any idea how many electrical devices give off radiation?
所有的
All of them.
我看我整晚都要呆这了
I'm gonna be here all night.
各有各的苦
Everybody's a whiner.
做实事, 不要做跟屁虫
Be a doer, not a me too-er.
继续加
Raise.
不跟了
I'm out.
她至少用四种止痛片
she's got at least four different types of pain pills here
还有一个LED设备
and an led device.
我跟而且大你
I'll raise your raise.
继续找
Keep looking.
不跟了
Fold.
你在虚张声势
you were bluffing.
而他知道你在虚张声势
He knew you were bluffing.
你今晚运气开始变差了
Your luck's changing tonight.
找到什么线索没?
So did they find anything?
还是你必须接受现实
Or are you gonna have to accept the fact
有时肿瘤就是会自然好
that every now and then remissions happen?
最好这个电话内容能有些价值
This call had better be worth my time.
她那时还不是我们的病人
This is what happens when it's not our patient.
我们信息有限
We don't know enough.
所以才让你去的
That's why you're there.
她有男朋友
She's got a boyfriend.
难道他有辐射...
Unless you think he's radioactive...
他随时会回来
he could show up any minute.
很荣幸为你工作
The honor of working for you
但被判入室抢劫就太不值了
is not worth a felony charge.
稍等一下
Give me a minute.
我觉得你拿到同花的几率
I'm saying the odds of you having a straight flush
非常小
are pretty low.
House!
我不跟
I'll fold.
不跟
Fold.
这下我瞎了
I'm screwed,aren't I?
同花才赢了9美金
Nine bucks for a straight flush.
他不会回家的
He's not coming home.
放心
Relax.
世界上没有什么东西
There's nothing in this universe
可以得到终极解释
that can't be explained...eventually.
比如这个牌局
Take this game.
只有两个人知道你想参加
Only two people knew that you wanted in on it.
我没跟他说
I didn't tell him.
我跟你说了我没告诉他
I told you, I didn't tell him.
怎么可能?
Why would you?
他唯一走的比较近的可以交谈的人碰巧是
The only person he's been getting all intimate and conversational with
你的患癌症的小可怜
is your cancer chick.
她怎么会知道?
How would she know?
牌局的话题
The subject of my poker game
不是病人如何交谈
isn't likely to come up in the course of a patient interview.
那些话是你对那些
No,that's the kind of thing you mention to someone
分享你全天生活的人说的
you're used to sharing the details of you day with.
别说了
Don'T.
你的拉比(犹太教学者)...
Your rabbi...
你的监护人
a guidance counselor.
一个母亲
A parent.
她不会是你妈妈吧?
She's not your mom, is she?
我很认真地告诉你别说了
I'm seriously saying don'T.
你和她上过床...
You've been having sex...
不该在这说的
this is so not the place.
和那个医学奇迹上床
With our miracle woman.
打扰了, 我可以...可以和你说几句么?
Excuse me,am I...may I talk to you?
当然可以
Of course.
Boyd正在穿衣服
Boyd's getting dressed.
他准备出院了
He's ready to check out.
你没同意他不能出院
He can't check out without your permission.
他的钠离子水平仍然不正常
His sodium level still isn't normal.
我和他说了, 他说上帝告诉他可以
I told him. He said that god said it was okay.
他没事了
He was fine.
你能和他谈谈么?
Could you talk to him?
告诉他们我不叫Wilson
Tell them my name isn't wilson.
大部人在你这种情况下
Most people in your situation
只会为事业发愁
just have their careers to worry about.
你除了事业最好担心一下神的惩罚
You've got that and divine retribution.
告诉他们真相
Tell them.
告诉他们这一切是怎么发生的
Tell me how it happened,
还有你想要达到的目的
and I'll tell them whatever you want.
她那天情况很糟
She'd had a bad day.
很痛苦
Pain-wise.
他朋友也没有来接她回家
Her ride didn't show up to take her home.
所以你送她了
So you offered.
没错
Yeah.
家里一点日用品都没有
She didn't have any groceries.
她病得太厉害出不了门
She was too sick to go out.
我想我能抽出半小时帮帮她
I figured I could afford to take a half hour.
送她, 买东西
Pick her up and few things.
然后留下确保她没事
And stay and make sure she's okay.
恩
Yeah.
然后就过夜了
And never leave.
你说你租了套房子
You told me you got an apartment.
但你事实上搬到她那住了
But you moved in with her.
你骗我
You lied to me.
告诉他们真相
Tell them.
他的名字不是Wilson
His name is not wilson,
他比我还混蛋
and he's screwed up worse than I am.
好吧, 我是骗了你
Okay,yes, I lied to you.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
肿瘤科医生多半对生死已经麻木了
Half the doctors who specialize in oncology,turn into burnt out cases.
而你呢? 被人需要是你的嗜好
But you,you eat neediness.
祝你好运
Lucky for you.
今天玩得很开心
Thanks for the game,guys.
我想我不会再来了
I don't think i'll be coming back.
你是只有用的吸血鬼
You're a functional vampire.
你救人, 你对社会有贡献
Sure,you're heroic, useful to society.
因为社会提供你需要的东西
But only because it feeds you.
我家没什么可偷的
There's nothing worth stealing,
看都别看
so don't even look.
你不仅迷恋楚楚可怜的人
You don't just have a fetish for needy people,
你娶了他们
you marry them!
- 又来了,- 你自找的
- Here we go!,- You mean it!
一段时间以后
And then time passes,
他们不再那么可怜了
suddenly they're not so needy anymore.
你的错
Your fault.
太照顾他们了
You've been there for them too much.
他们变得健康, 独立
They're getting healthy, independent.
然后你觉得他们没那么美了
And that's just ugly.
我的天, 你现在一定恨死上帝了
God,you must be pissed at god right now.
让她那么快乐
Making her all happy.
为什么你要说这些?
Why are you doing this?
因为你太蠢了
Because you're being stupid.
你知道和病人睡觉要冒很大的风险
You know what you're risking by sleeping with a patient.
狗屁
Oh,that's crap.
你火冒三丈不是担心我的前途
You're not mad because i'm risking my job.
也不是因为我骗了你
You're not even mad because I lied to you.
真正的原因是我骗了你而你没发现
You're mad because i lied to you, and you couldn't tell.
你说对了
Yeah,you got me nailed.
所以你不希望我参加牌局
Yeah,that's why you didn't want me in your poker game.
因为如果一切都在掌握之中
Because when it comes to being in control,
你就会把那个靠信仰治病的孩子忘到九霄云外
gregory house leaves our faith healer kid in the dust.
所以宗教信仰让你恼火
And that's why religious belief annoys you.
因为如果世间万物都能用理论解释
Because if the universe operates by abstract rules,
你能学习理论并用理论保护自己
you can learn them, you can protect yourself.
如果上帝存在的话
If a supreme being exists,
随时都可以把你捏扁
he can squash you any time he wants.
他知道我在哪
He knows where I am.
你的电话
I think it's yours.
什么事
Yeah.
我马上来
I'll be right there.
"耶稣"发了高烧
Jesus is spiking a fever.
产生了幻觉
He's delusional.
结节性脑硬化不会引起发烧
Tuberous sclerosis doesn't cause fever.
我知道
I know.
我来开
I'll drive.
街上随便找个人
pick any random guy off the street.
把他带来
Bring him in here,
彻底检查一下
examine him exhaustively.
会发现不下三个地方有毛病
You will find at least three things wrong with him.
这孩子得的是结节性脑硬化
This kid has tuberous sclerosis.
但不太严重
A mild case.
但他的脑瘤正在变大
But his tumors are growing.
我们只是推测在变大
We assumed that the tumors were growing.
因为病得更厉害了
'Cause he's getting sicker.
但是如果不是来医院检查
But he could have grown old and died
他可能变老去世后也不会知道得了这病
and never known about them if he hadn't come here.
我们要找的东西
We were looking for something
应该在他右半脑的什么位置
that was more or less in the right part of the brain.
就像我们发现有人
It's like we found someone
站在受害者身边手里拿着枪
standing over a dead body holding a gun.
就会马上逮捕, 不再追查
We arrested them,didn't look any further.
但是有时候
Well,sometimes
那人确实只是偶然闯入了犯罪现场
people really do just stumble into a murder scene.
体温摄氏39.4度, 还在继续升高
His fever is 103 and rising.
如果不采取什么措施
If we don't do anything,
他马上就真的去见上帝了
he's gonna be chatting with god face to face real soon.
高烧不会由长期潜伏的病症引发
Fevers don't come from a long-term underlying condition.
他那批狂热的信徒中
He's a garden variety religious nut
有人传染给他了
who happens to have an infection.
给他做腰椎穿刺术
It's lumbar puncture time.
不行
No.
绝不, 上帝告诉我不能再用人类的药物了
No,god told me no more of man's medicine.
只要我信仰上帝, 他会把我治好的
If we have faith in him, he'll make me well.
只是做个检验
It's just a test.
我们只是想知道哪出了问题
We just wanna find out what's wrong.
上帝知道哪出了问题
God knows what's wrong.
上帝会治好我的
God will take care of it.
他现在神志不清, 还是未成年人
He's delirious, and he's a minor.
要由你来做决定, 不是他
This is your decision, and not his.
天国像是
The kingdom of heaven is like
藏在田野的宝藏
a treasure hidden in field
当你发现时
which when a man finds,
他又藏了起来
heides.
会很乐意变卖家产把那块土地买下来
For joy he goes and sells all he owns and buys that field.
你想买哪就买哪
Buy all the land you want!
别和你的大脑过不去
Don't blow your brains out.
你在眼睁睁看着你的孩子自杀
You're watching your son kill himself!
发烧使他神志不清
He's out of his mind with fever.
爸爸, 如果你的信仰不够坚定
Dad,if your faith is weak,
我会被上帝遗弃
I will fail.
我需要你的支持
I need you.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你们甚至不知道他得了什么病
You don't even know what's wrong with him.
但上帝知道
God knows the answer.
与其相信你们我宁可托付给上帝
And I would rather leave it in his hands than yours.
Wilson.
Wilson
该你出马了
I need you to do your thing.
你知道我不是真的有魔力吧?
You do know that I don't actually have magical powers.
我对你有信心
I have faith.
你最好在他的饭菜里下些抗生素
You're better off trying to slip some antibiotics into a meal...
哪种?
which antibiotics?
我们不知道他感染了什么
We don't know what infection he's got.
越广谱越好
Go as broad as you can.
算了吧
Forget it.
最大的希望就是你那三寸不烂之舌
Our best hope is your silver tongue.
如果不是感染呢?
What if it's not an infection?
你有没有用心
Where you not paying attention
听我讲犯罪现场的比喻?
when I was doing my murder scene metaphor?
如果结节性脑硬化的确是凶手?
What if the tuberous sclerosis is guilty?
手里拿着枪
It had the gun in its hand,
站在...
it was standing over...
不会引发高烧
doesn't cause fever.
会导致其他症状
It causes everything else.
如果高烧就是无辜的旁观者?
What if the fever's the innocent bystander?
高烧可以由他接触的任何东西引发
Fever could have been set off,by something he picked up anywhere.
比如医院里的一只小虫
Could have been a bug he got here.
或是他带来的小虫
Or a bug he gave here.
他传染给你的病人
He gave it to your patient.
所以肿瘤变小了
That's why her tumor shrank.
因为病毒先杀死癌细胞
The virus went after the cancer first.
你指病毒攻击了她的肿瘤?
Are you saying a virus attacked her tumor?
200年来
For 200 years,
有许多病例发现野生型病毒会攻击癌细胞
there have been reports of wild viruses that target tumors.
19世纪初
Early 1900s,
一期意大利医学杂志,报道了一个患子宫癌的妇女
an italian medical journal wrote up a woman with cervical cancer
通过注射一种活性不强的狂犬病毒治疗
who was injected with a weak strain of rabies.
我不知道怎么会想到这么做
I have no idea why they did that,
但是她的肿瘤萎缩了
but her tumor shrank.
你觉得他把狂犬病传染给了她?
You think he gave her rabies?
一种倾向于攻击癌细胞的病毒
One of the virus types most prone to go after cancer cells
就是疱疹
is herpes.
疱疹病毒性脑炎
Herpes encephalitis.
符合所有的情况
It would fit.
癫痫发作, 钠离子水平过低
Seizure,low sodium.
还有视觉模糊
Even the blurred vision.
而且这意味着
And it would mean
如果你是对的
if you're right,
Grace的癌症会继续恶化
grace's cancer is coming back.
你不可能说服他们的
You're not gonna be able to convince them.
他们拒绝任何的检验
They don't want any more tests.
不愿意...
They don't wanna...
"该隐的记号"可以让他们屈服,(该隐是圣经中人物)
they can't argue with the mark of cain.
我不会改变主意的
I'm not gonna change my mind.
不做任何检验
No more tests.
上帝会料理一切的
God knows the way.
好吧, 我们从衬衣开始
Okay,let's start with his shirt.
你要做什么?
What are you doing?
这是上帝指派的任务
I'm on a mission from god.
如果你不让我脱
If you won't let me undress you,
那就自己脱
then strip.
他在做什么? 究竟怎么回事?
What's he doing? What's going on?
你帮助的那个女人被你传染了病毒
That woman you helped, you gave her a virus.
不, 她康复了, 我有这种天分...
No,she's healed. I have a gift--
珠宝,袜子才叫礼物,(英文中礼物和天分拼写一致)
a gift is jewelry,socks.
你有的只是疱疹病毒性脑炎
What you have is herpes encephalitis.
传播的唯一途径是
The only way you could have transmitted it
接触过你的疮后
is by scratching one of your own sores
再接触其他人
and touching another person.
疱疹是通过性交传染的, 不是么?
Herpes,that's something you get from sex,right?
性交或是唇疱疹传播
Either that or cold sores.
你孩子是通过性交传染的
Your kid got it from the sex.
没有什么疮
No,no sores.
我的身体是洁净的
No,my body is clean.
住院时给我检查过了, 没有什么疮
They examined me when I came in. No sores.
疱疹有潜伏期
Herpes hides.
发作之后会消失
You have an outbreak, it goes away,
再出现, 再消失...
comes back,goes away.
脱!
Strip!
你刚来时没有疮
You didn't have a sore when you came in,
但现在有了
but you've got one now.
爸爸, 我从来不会...
Dad,I've never ever--
你也觉得很奇怪为什么上帝选中的孩子
you ever wonder why a perfect child of god
急着想要证明自己的纯洁无瑕
should feel so desperate to purify his body
而每天都要喝下几加仑的水吧?
that he needed to scarf down a dozen gallons of water a day?
Boyd, 是真的吗?
Boyd,is he right?
爸爸, 不是, 他有病!
Dad,no,he's crazy.
你要帮我
Help me.
Wilson医生, 帮我!
Dr. Wilson,help!
上帝只说了不要吃药, 不要治疗
God said no medicine, no procedures.
没说不能脱衣服
Taking off your clothes doesn't count as either of those.
你来决定
This one's your call.
儿子...
Son...
爸爸, 你要相信我
dad,you have to have faith in me.
我只相信上帝
I have faith in the lord.
对你, 我也信任
You,I trust.
恰如一个少年所能得到的信任
As much as you can trust a teenage boy.
把衣服脱了
Take off your clothes.
放轻松点
Relax.
祷告几句圣母玛利亚, 几片阿昔洛韦
A few hail marys, a little acyclovir.
你马上又可以和天使们约会了
You'll be picking up angels again in no time.
进来
Come in.
父亲要我向你道歉
My father told me i have to apologize to you.
还有幻听么?
Still hearing voices?
你很幸运
You're lucky.
你始终相信你是对的
You go through life with a certainty that what you're doing is right.
我知道那种感觉很好
I know how comforting that is.
祝你好运
Good luck..
你不肯给我最后的一分?
You're not gonna give me my final point?
你知道是我说的?
You knew it was me?
还会有谁?
Who else?
你不觉得上帝应该扣一分吗?
You don't think god should get a point knocked off?
肿瘤萎缩了
The tumor shrank.
那是因为病毒
Because of a virus.
你知道概率有多小么?
Do you know what the odds are?
她正好是那种癌症
She had to have the right type of cancer.
他正好是那种病毒
He had to have the right type of virus.
必须接触...
The exposure had to be--
她中了彩票
she won the lottery.
你说她中了彩票
You say won the lottery,
用他的话说...这是神迹
he says...miracle.
没错, 上帝的手伸进了男孩的裤衩
Yeah,the hand of god reached into this kid's pants,
让他性交, 抓了抓疮口
made him have sex so he could scratch a rash,
手指去摸女人的脸
stick his fingers in some woman's face,
结果那女人多活了几个月
give her a few extra months.
得了, 他只是个喜欢操纵别人的骗子
Come on,he's just another liar and manipulator.
没有人和你一样完美
Well,nobody's as perfect as you are.
有可能人们有了信仰
It is possible to believe in something
却无法做到
and still fail to live up to it.
你女朋友怎么样了?
So,how's your girlfriend?
她争取了一些时间
She got a little extra time out of this
但是不多
not a lot.
她没有崩溃?
She didn't crash?
没有...
No...
她说她有所信仰时会更快乐
she says she's happier when she believes in something bigger than she is.
她仍然有信仰
She still believes.
一种信念
Faith.
她要去佛罗伦萨
She's going to florence.
你搬出来?
You moving out?
是啊
Yeah.
回来和我住?
Moving back in with me?
我不觉得这是个好主意
I don't think that's a great idea.
我们还是朋友
But we're okay.
House, 你简直...
House,you are...
上帝就是这么造你的
as god made you.